Guide to the Jack Rottier photographs and papers of the C and O Canal, 1952-1974 MS2037
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Towpath on C&O canal, 1968 April (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Text with photograph: "4 x 4 color photo of towpath, C&O canal, April 1968"
  Text with negative: "2 1/4 x 2 1/4 color negative towpath on C&O canal, April 1968"
- Towpath near Fletcher's, 1968 April (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Text with photograph: "4 x 4 color photo of towpath near Fletchers April 1968."
  Text with negative: "2 1/4 x 2 1/4 color transparency, towpath near Fletcher's April 1968."
- C&O hike, 1968 April 26 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Text with photograph: "11007-11 3-W to 3-2; 4-A to 4-H 12 B&W photoproofs Douglas Hire, 4-26-69 3-W Fort Frederick 4-B W. Dean McClanahan, Supt C&O NWP 4-C Justice Douglas, Cathy Douglas 4-F Anita Rollins, Cathy & Justice Douglas with Hagerstown Paper 4-G Congressman Lilbert Gude, Grant Conway 4-H Colin ritter, Gilbert Gude, Grant Conway
- Girl wading in stream, 1969 May (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Text on photograph: "50-D"
  Text with photograph: "3 x 5 color photo of girl wading in stream, dated May 1969"
- Kayak in stream, 1969 May (Box 2, Folder 4)
  Text with photograph: "3 x 5 color photo of kayak in stream, dated May 1969"
  Text on photograph: "50-R"
- C&O Canal Association Banquet, 1968 April 27 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  Text with program: "program, banquet, C&O Canal Association 14th Annual Reunion, April 27, 1968"
  Text on program: "Justice Douglas- Washington Post Hike, March 19, 1954 C&O Canal Association 14th Annual Reunion Banquet Sepherd College Shepherdstown, West Virginia April 27, 1968"
- Hikers Guide to the C. & O. Canal, 1968 April 27 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  Text with pamphlet: "Pamphlet, "Hikers Guide to the C&O Canal," by Grant Conway, April 27, 1968 - Advance Release"
- Sketch map of Shepard College, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Stream in canoe, 1969 May (Box 2, Folder 8)
  Text with photograph: "3 x 5 photo of canoe in stream, dated May 69"
  Text on photograph: "50-4"
- Kayak in stream, 1969 May (Box 2, Folder 9)
  Text with photograph: "3 x 5 color photo of kayak in stream, May 1969."
  Text on photograph: "50-W"
- Note to Jack Rottier from Grant Midgley, 1975 January 18 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  Text with note: "Note to Jack Rottier from Grant Midgley, with 2 attachments, annotated paper, "47 follow Justice Douglas route on C&O canal," unsigned, with 1 copy, February 18, 1975"
- Hikers on towpath, 1969 May (Box 2, Folder 11)
  Text with photograph: "3 x 5 color photo of hikers on towpath, dated May 1969"
  Text on photograph: "51-D"
- Hikers on towpath, 1969 May (Box 2, Folder 12)
  Text with photograph: "3 x 5 color photo of hikers on towpath, May 1969"
  Text on photograph: "51-F"
- Hikers crossing upstream, 1969 May (Box 2, Folder 13)
  Text with photograph: "3 x 5 color photo, May 1969 hikers crossing upstream end of aqueduct, Justice Douglas & Cathy in center. Ken Rollins with camera to right. Douglas Greene at far right with 2 canteens.
- Aqueduct, 1969 May (Box 2, Folder 14)
  Text with photograph: "3 x 5 color photo of aqueduct, c&o canal, May 1969"
  Text on photograph: "51-H"
- Hikers on towpath, 1969 May (Box 2, Folder 15)
  Text on photograph: "51-L"
- Douglas hike, 1969 April 26 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  Text with photographs: "11004 2-y to 2-z, 3-A to 3-J 12 B&W photoproofs Douglas hike, 4-26-1969 2-y & 2-z - looking across prism toward river, MP69, Antietam level 3-A - Antietam creek aqueduct 3-B - H - Hikers at upstream end of aqueduct. Douglas in center hat in hand 3-l - Douglas (black jacket) with hikers, George Kline behind hikers"
- C & O hike, 1969 April 26 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  Text with contact sheets: "12 B&W photo proofs 11004 4-I to 4-T (2 copies) Banquet, Douglas Hike, 4-26-69 4-I - banquet scene in coolfont barn 4-j - at left leaning over, Tom Conlon, Mayor of Cumberland 4-K - J.C.S (Jack) Durham 4-L - Douglas, Grant Conway speaking 4-M - Jack Durham's back 4-N - Smith Brookhart standing 4-Q - Grant Conway (drinking), Douglas 4-R - Douglas, Ralph Donnely 4-S - Douglas"
- C & O Hike, 1969 April 26 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  Text with contact sheet: "11004 - 3-K to 3-V 12 B&W photo proofs Douglas reunion hike, 4-26-69"
- Justice Douglas, 1969 April 26 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  Text with photograph: "11004-A - probably Douglas Hike, 4-26-69. Justice Douglas 5 x 7 B&W photo"
- Justice Douglas and Senator Charles Mathis, 1969 April 26 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  Text with photograph: "8 x 10 B&W photo, probably from Douglas hike on 4-26-69 Justice Douglas & Senator Charles Mathis"
- Justice Douglas, 1969 April 26 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  Text with photograph: "8 x 10 B&W photo - Justice Douglas, probably at Douglas hike on 4-26-69"
  Justice Douglas with unidentified man and woman
- Excerpt from Congressional Record, 1970 August 13 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  Text with excerpt: "Excerpt from Congressional Record, Testimony of Senator Mathias on C&O Canal National Historical Park, August 13, 1970"
- Douglas Hike, 1971 May 01 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  Text with contact sheet: "11004 - 12-F to 12-I 4 B&W photo proofs, 5-1-71 Douglas hike, April 1971"
- Douglas Hike, 1971 May 01 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  Text with contact sheet: "11004 11-X to 11-Z, 12-A to 12-E 8 B&W photo proofs, 5-1-71 Douglas hike, April 1971 11-X to 11-Z, Justice & Mrs. Douglas 12-B -, Representative Henry Reuss 12-C - Hikers assembling at Spring Gap for 1971 hike 12-D - Congressman Reuss, Ranger Maurice Sullivan, "Scully", _ "
- Douglas Hike, 1971 May 01 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  Text with contact sheet: "11004 - 11-P to 11-W 8 B&W photo proof, 5-1-71 Douglas hike, April 1971 11-P - Approach Lock 72, 11-Q - Justice & Mrs. Douglas, Gilbert Gude 11-T - Lock 72 11-V - Ranger Maurice Sullivan 11-W - Tom Conlon - Mayor of Cumberland,, _"
- Douglas hike, 1971 May 01 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  Text with contact sheet: "11004 - 11-H to 11-O 8 B&W photo proofs, 5-1-71 Douglas hike, April 1971 11-L - Barbara Yeaman (Former President of C&O Canal Association) & Edwin (Ed) Wesely"
- Douglas hike, 1971 May 01 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  Text with contact sheet: "11004 - 10-Z, 11-A to 11-G 8 B&W photo proofs, 5-1-1971 Douglas hike, April 1971"
- Robin Rottier and Candy Clay, 1971 April (Box 2, Folder 28)
  Text on photograph: "Sore feet after passing 181- mile marker Robin Rottier & Candy Clay of Annandale, Va"
  Text with photograph: "5 x 7 B&W photo, Robin Rottier & Caudy Clay at MP 181, C&O canal, April 1971"
- Douglas hike, 1971 April (Box 2, Folder 29)
  Text with contact sheet: "11004 10-R to 10X 8 B&W photo proofs, 5-1-71 Douglas hike, April 1971"
- Douglas hike, 1971 May 01 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  Text with contact sheet: "11004- 10-J to 10-Q, DTS 5-1-71 8 B&W photo proofs April 1971 Douglas hike,"
- Hike map, Circa 1973 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  Text with map: "copy, hike map, section from below MP41 to above MP 42, ca. 1973"
- PEPCO vs. the C and O Canal, Circa 1973 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  Text with document: "copy, 2-page, back-to-back paper, "PEPCO vs. the C and O Canal, ca 1973"
- Paper by Jack Rottier, 1974 April 17-24 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  Text with document: "6-page handwritten untitled, undated paper by Jack Rottier describing April 17 - 24, 1971 C&O Canal Association hike"
- C&O Canal Association 20th Anniversary Reunion Hike, 1974 April 17-27 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  Text with document: "booklet, "C&O Canal Association 20th Anniversary Reunion Hike, April 17-27, 1974" with list of hikers and press clippings"
- Girl in Hammock, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  Text with photograph: "Girl in hammock is probably Mary Heimer, age 15 who hiked full length of canal in 1974 or 1979"
- Dick Stanton and Walter McMann, 1974 April 18 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  Text on photograph: " Ranger Walter McMann Dick Stanton Sept. 19 - 1989"
  Text with photograph: "Dick Stanton & Walter McMann at Stickpile Hill, April 18, 1974"
- Unidentified house, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)